cooper.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy Statement - Cooper

Objective:

Cooper values and respects your privacy.  This Privacy Statement describes the privacy policies followed by Cooper Software, Inc., a California corporation (“Cooper,” “we,” “our,” or “us”), and how we collect and process information obtained from you when you communicate with us, including via this website. 

Cooper does not generally require your personal information to visit and use the website. However, you may be required to provide your personal information to participate in certain activities, such as a general request for information, signing up for a newsletter, or signing up for a training course. You may not be able to participate in these activities if you choose not to provide your personal information. By providing personal information to us, you explicitly agree to our collection and use of all such information as described in this Privacy Statement.

Scope of this Privacy Statement:

Cooper may provide links to third-party websites for your convenience and information. If you access any such links through the Cooper website, you may leave our website. We do not control those sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from Cooper’s practices. The personal information you choose to provide to or that is collected by these third parties is not covered by Cooper’s Privacy Statement.  

Personal information collected by Cooper:

We may collect personal information such as your First Name, Last Name, E-mail Address, Job Title, Organization Name, Country, City and Phone Number (including mobile/cell) or other personal information that you may include in an email or other communication to Cooper.  When you provide information that enables us to respond to your request for products or services, we will, wherever permissible by relevant laws, collect, use and disclose this information to third parties for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement.  When you provide us your mobile phone number, you consent to the use of your mobile phone number for the purposes identified in this Privacy Statement. 

In addition, you can engage with us through social media. When you do so, you may allow us to access certain information from your social media profile based upon your privacy preference settings on that platform.  

Cooper will not be liable for any unsolicited information provided by you. You consent to Cooper using such information in the manner set forth in this Privacy Statement.

How We Use your Data:

The personal information we collect may be used to:

  * provide information and services as requested by you
  * assess queries, requirements, and process requests for information and services
  * perform client communication, service, billing and administration
  * conduct data analysis
  * assess web site performance and usage analysis
  * maintain leads
  * run marketing or promotional campaigns
  * conduct processing necessary to fulfill other contractual obligations for the individual.

With your consent, we may also use your personal information for additional purposes. Instances where sensitive personal information is collected will warrant explicit consent. Unless it is necessary for our legitimate business purposes, should you choose not to provide any personal information during certain activity, you will nevertheless be able to continue with such activity wherever possible.  

Sharing of personal information with third parties:

Cooper does not share personal information about you with affiliates, partners, service providers, or non-affiliated companies except: (a) to provide products or services you’ve requested; (b) when we have your permission: or (c) under the following circumstances:

  * We may share information with affiliates, our parent company (Wipro), and subsidiaries for legitimate business purposes.
  * We may provide the information to trusted entities who work on our behalf, and may use your personal information to help us communicate with you about offers from us and for other legitimate business purposes. 
  * We may share information with statutory authorities, government institutions or other bodies where required for compliance with legal requirements.
  * We may use the information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.
  * We may share information where we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action against any illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or as otherwise required by law.
  * We may share information where we believe it is necessary in order to protect Cooper’s rights, usage terms, intellectual or physical property or for the safety of Cooper or others.
  * We may share information about you if Cooper is acquired by or merged with another company.

Data Protection and Confidentiality: 

Cooper has implemented reasonable and adequate physical, technical and administrative security measures to protect personal information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction.

Cooper discloses information to third parties only for legitimate purposes, such as to our service providers and agents who are bound to maintain the confidentiality of personal information and may not use the information for any unauthorized purpose. 

Further, Cooper may make disclosures to law enforcement authorities or regulatory bodies subject to applicable law.

Cooper will take reasonable steps to ensure that all dealings in Personal Information shall:

  * be processed fairly & lawfully
  * be obtained only with the consent of the information provider;
  * only be collected, when the information is collected for a legitimate purpose connected with a function or activity of Cooper; 
  * be available for review by the information provider, as and when requested.
  * be kept secure against unauthorized or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage, as per the prescribed standards.

Cooper’s Commitment Regarding Personal information:

Cooper wants to ensure that our users can protect their interests in their personal information.  This is why we want to ensure that you have the ability to:

  * Access your personal information
  * Correct your personal information
  * Erase your personal information
  * Limit processing of your personal information 
  * Object to processing of your personal information
  * Obtain a portable version of your personal information
  * Withdraw your consent to Cooper’s use of your personal information

We will provide you with the ability to determine whether or not we process your personal information and, where we do, obtain access to the personal information, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal information concerned and the recipients of the personal information, if any. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply you a copy of your personal information. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.

We will provide you with the ability to have any inaccurate personal information about you rectified and, where applicable, to have any incomplete personal information about you completed.

Under some circumstances we will provide you with the ability to have your personal information erased without undue delay. These circumstances include one or more of the following: your personal information is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal information have been unlawfully processed. However, we will not erase personal information that we believe is or may be necessary for Cooper to comply with a legal obligation, or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

Under some circumstances we will provide you with the ability to restrict the processing of your personal information. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal information; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal information for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal information for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection.  Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal information. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

We will provide you with the ability to object to our processing of your personal information on grounds relating to your particular situation.  However, we will not erase personal information that we believe is or may be necessary for Cooper to comply with a legal obligation, or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

We will provide you with the ability to object to our processing of your personal information for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal information for this purpose.

To the extent that the basis for our processing of your personal information is: (a) consent; or (b) that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, we will provide you with the ability to receive your personal information from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

If you believe that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence or your place of work.

To the extent that the basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, we will provide you with the ability to withdraw that consent at any time.  If, for example, you request electronic communications from us, such as a newsletter, you will be able to unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions included in the communication.  Withdrawal of your consent will not be applicable to Cooper’s processing of your personal information before a reasonable time for Cooper to address your withdrawal of consent.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal information by contacting us at support@cooper or com or by mailing us at the following address:

    Cooper

450 Sansome St. 

9th Floor

San Francisco, CA 94111  

Retention of personal information:

We will retain your personal information for as long as necessary to provide the services you have requested, or for other essential purposes such as performance of a contract, complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes, and enforcing our policies.

Children’s Privacy:  

Cooper strongly believes in protecting children’s privacy rights.  Our website is not intended to be used by children under age 13. We do not intend to collect personal information through our Services from children under age 13, and if we receive information that we have collected any such information about a child under age 13, we will delete that information and not use or disclose it except as may be required by law. If you are a parent or legal guardian and believe your child under age 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, you can write us at the address provided at the end of this Privacy Statement or by emailing support@cooper.com. Please use “COPPA Information Request” in the subject line of your communication.

Your California Privacy Rights:  

If you are a California resident, the following section describes your additional privacy rights.

**“Shine the Light” Law**

Under California’s “Shine the Light” law, if you provide personal information to obtain products or services for personal, family, or household use, you are entitled to request and obtain from us once per calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses.  You may request information about our compliance with the Shine the Light law by: (1) contacting us by email to support@cooper.com with “Request for California Privacy Information” in the subject line; or (2) by sending a letter to the address at the end of this Privacy Statement, Attn: “Request for California Privacy Information.” Any such request must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the description and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code.   We will provide the requested information to you by email, if you emailed us, or by regular mail, if you mailed us. Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the “Shine the Light” requirements and only information on covered sharing will be included in our response.

**California “Do Not Track” Disclosures**

Our Web server automatically recognizes and stores certain computer-readable information, such as your IP address and domain name combination. This is typically anonymous information automatically provided by your computer. We use this information to follow visitor usage patterns in order to improve user experience. If your Internet browser employs blocking or “Do Not Track” technology that limits recognition or the collection of such computer-readable information, Cooper will not alter or bypass such technology. 

International transfer of Personal Information:

We may transfer to, and store the data we collect about you in, countries other than the country in which the data was originally collected, including the United States, Canada or other destinations outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or Switzerland. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you provided the data. When we transfer your data to other countries, we will protect the data as described in this Privacy Statement and comply with applicable legal requirements providing adequate protection for the transfer of data to countries outside the EEA or Switzerland.

If you are located in the EEA, we will only transfer your personal data if:

  * the country to which the personal data will be transferred has been granted a European Commission adequacy decision; or
  * the recipient of the personal data is located in the US and has certified to the US-EU Privacy Shield Framework; or
  * we have put in place appropriate safeguards in respect of the transfer, for example we have entered into EU standard contractual clauses with the recipient, or the recipient is a party to binding corporate rules.

Contact us:

If you have any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Statement or processing of your personal information, please send an email to support@cooper.com or contact us by writing to:

Cooper Software, Inc.

450 Sansome, 9th Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94111

Effective Date and Changes to this Privacy Statement:

Please note that this Privacy Statement may be subject to change from time to time.  The revised Privacy Statement will accordingly be published on this page.   Please regularly check this Privacy Statement to ensure you are aware of the latest updates with respect to the same.

This Privacy Statement was last updated on June 14, 2019.
